Alberto Marín García

Software Engineer

노 +34 618 04 23 47 @ alberto.marin@gmail.com 🕜 https://portfolio.albertomarin.info

SUMMARY

Software Engineer since 2001 with extensive experience in the software development life cycle of products and custom projects, using agile methodologies, common design patterns and SOLID principles.

Worked extensively in the analysis and design of Java Web Applications addressed at automating the business processes in the purchasing department of sectors as diverse as Telecom, Pharma, Steel & Mining, Ventilation, Oil & Gas, Public and Airlines among others.

Between 2006 and 2020 my work was used by almost 100 companies in 10 countries with thousands suppliers and it has integrated with ERPs like Microsoft Dynamics, SAP, Oracle JD Edwards, IBM AS/400 and Movex.

Since 2019 I enjoy developing Mobile Apps using Expo, React Native, React Navigation and React Redux.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Webfleet Solutions 11/2020 - Ongoing Barcelona, Spain

Software Architect

CLEVER Global 01/2006 - 2020 Barcelona, Spain

- Responsible for the development and evolution of iQuotes Suite®, a
 Java Web Application for strategic purchasing management
- Designed and implemented iQuotes Suite® projects that integrates with clients' ERPs and Marketplaces, including functional APIs, single sign-on, integrated look-and-feel and deployment in multiple platforms like BEA WebLogic, JBoss, Tomcat and IBM WebSphere

Programmer Analyst

Softtek 08/2004 - 09/2005 Coruña, Spain

 Developed, updated, and maintained ASP Web Applications for Caixa Galicia

Programmer Analyst

Wincor Nixdorf 01/2001 - 12/2003 Caracas, Venezuela

- Developed a VB6/COM+ windows-based module of INFINIX TransX solution related to the banking area for Corp Banca
- Designed and implemented several software solutions for Interactive Kiosk Terminals for Banesco and Banco de Venezuela

TECHNOLOGIES

Java Servl		vlets & JSP	SQL	Toplink	Jenkins & ANT	
CVS & Git		Node.js	AWS	S Firebase	Serverless	
React Native React			Navigati	on React	: Redux	Expo

LANGUAGES

Spanish English

STRENGTHS

- ★ Analytical with long-term product vision
- Committed to the application of best practices in software development
- Lifelong learning
- Great team player
- Polyglot programming

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Amazon Web Services, 2018

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Amazon Web Services, 2018

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

Oracle, 2017

Mobile Startup Engineering Bootcamp

KeepCoding®, 2016-2017

Design Patterns in Java LiveLessons

Addison-Wesley Professional, 2015

Gamification

University of Pennsylvania Online Course, 2015

Professional Scrum Master I

Scrum.org, 2014

Master in Software Engineering

Fundació Politècnica de Catalunya. Barcelona, Spain, 2005-2007

Developing and Implementing Web Applications with Microsoft Visual $C\#^{TM}$.NET and Microsoft Visual Studio .NET

Microsoft, 2005

English as a Second Language Course, Intermediate Level

LSC Toronto, Canada, 1999

Degree in Computer Engineering

Simón Bolívar University. Caracas, Venezuela, 1995-2001